First of all, I would like to thank Mr. Zach for sharing with us.
Please follow Mr. Zach's Artstation account after the live broadcast.
The next part of our Marvelous Designer team preparation is the content of our physical properties summary.
Before I officially tell you about our physical properties, I need to describe some of the settings in our software.
I am playing a recorded video, so during the viewing process, I will pause to see your chats and answer your questions.
First of all, in Marvelous Designer,
when we are in the Fabric window,
after selecting a fabric, its specific properties will appear in the property editor at the bottom.
After we select a fabric, we can click on its preset to select the preset fabric properties at the bottom.
In the latest version, when we stop the mouse on these preset fabrics,
we can see the effect of these fabrics on a ball.
We will probably know what texture it is.
At the bottom, we can see its specific properties.
We can see the detail adjustment of the specific properties.
When we adjust the physical properties, we have several options.
First of all, these values are adjusted by 4 groups.
For example, the strength of the gold tail gauze is 4 groups.
The bend strength is also 4 groups.
The strength of the gold tail gauze, although its name is gold tail gauze,
and the bottom is the tension of the right foot line.
The tension of the right foot line is the stretch of the right foot line.
Then how do we know what the gold tail gauze of the fabric represents?
We need to use the editing text tool to select the sheet.
We can see that there is a arrow on this sheet.
The arrow direction is its gold shape and it has a 90 degree angle.
Now in the video, this orange position is our tail.
Why is there a gold shape and a tail shape?
Because our clothing fabric has two directions, the gold shape and the tail shape.
Its different direction is due to its different gauze lines.
Or the strength of the gauze line itself is different.
It will affect its specific physical properties.
So we are just like the earth.
So we are in Marvelous Designer.
First of all, you are rotating this gold tail gauze.
When the gold shape is marked, you can modify the position of the gold shape of each piece of fabric.
Why do we modify it?
It's because in Marvelous Designer,
every fabric, every sheet, when you create it, it's all gold in the vertical direction.
But after some adjustments and operations,
such as the joint sheet, or some other operations,
this sheet may rotate or
uh...
it will have some other adjustments,
resulting in a change in the direction of its fabric.
We may need to manually rotate it back to the vertical direction.
This can make it easy for us to adjust and determine the physical properties of the fabric.
I will put it in the live broadcast.
Okay, now when we select a sheet,
it goes back to what we said before.
In addition, we can check the fabric in the 2D window.
In addition to the gold tail gauze of its different positions,
we can also click on this sheet in the 3D window to see
the position of our click, the direction of the fabric's gauze.
For example, now I click on this position,
these two positions.
When I don't turn on the simulation,
in fact, the direction of its sheet is the same as that of the 2D window.
Right.
But when we turn on the simulation, it's different.
Because when we turn on the simulation,
you can imagine this sheet as a skirt.
Although we can see it with our naked eyes,
we will feel that its bottom is basically flat.
But in fact, its gold tail gauze,
its gold gauze tail gauze in this position,
is actually different from our 3D window,
which is the intuitive feeling.
In the middle position, its vertical direction is still the gold gauze.
This is no problem.
But when it comes to the two sides,
because this sheet is flat when it is in 2D,
when it is in 3D window simulation,
it will fall down.
So after it falls down,
in fact, its horizontal direction is its gold gauze.
The vertical direction is its tail gauze.
This also leads to the fact that if our fabric,
its physical properties,
for example, the gold gauze and the tail gauze are too different,
then its bottom may not be flat.
Now our gold gauze tail gauze is the same vertical.
Then we can modify it later.
For example, now,
the tail gauze,
let's reduce its strength a little bit.
First of all, the strength of the gold tail gauze,
and the tension of the corner line,
it controls the stretch performance of the fabric.
If this value is smaller,
it will stretch more easily.
If this value is larger,
it will not stretch more easily.
That is to say,
its fabric texture may become harder.
So now,
let's reduce the strength of the tail gauze
in its gold tail gauze.
Because of the strength of the tail gauze,
it only controls the stretch performance of the fabric on the tail.
So let's take a look at
how it will change in the 3D window on the left.
Okay,
do you still remember?
I just said that
the vertical direction of the fabric in the middle is the gold gauze,
and the vertical direction on both sides is the tail gauze.
So when you reduce the vertical strength of the tail gauze,
there is no effect on the middle position of this panel,
but it will have a great impact on both sides.
Because the vertical direction of the fabric on both sides is the tail gauze.
Can you understand?
So when you change this,
if you only change the strength of the tail gauze,
then it will only affect,
it will obviously affect the two sides,
the left and the right.
If I change the strength of the gauze now,
then it will be very difficult to change the strength of the tail gauze.
Then it is very obvious that it will affect the middle part,
and on both sides,
its influence is not so high.
So when we have a specific understanding of this physical property,
know these detail properties,
what kind of performance does it represent?
Before we need to know the performance of the fabric folding,
we need to know,
there is probably an understanding,
that is, this fabric has a gold-gauze shape.
Okay,
we just talked about the digital direction,
which is the gold-gauze shape.
That is, when we go to click on the board,
use the editing text tool to click on the board,
this arrow direction is the gold-gauze shape,
and it has a 90-degree angle,
which is the tail gauze.
Then there is a problem,
that is, we still have the angle direction.
The angle direction,
in fact, is the angle of these 45 degrees,
the angle direction,
in fact, it is easy to understand.
Then it will have a left angle and a right angle,
two directions.
Okay,
for example,
now I turn this gold-gauze direction to the left 45 degrees,
then it's this,
for example,
now my board,
after we have gone through some merger,
simulation,
or some adjustments,
for example,
the position it is in now,
I can see it with my own eyes,
this gold-gauze is 45 degrees,
then this vertical direction,
it is the right angle,
its vertical direction is the right angle.
Of course,
everyone may be a little tired now,
but it doesn't matter,
later you will find that
in fact,
if you are serious about
understanding this left-angle line and right-angle line,
you will find that
in fact,
their value is almost set,
only in a more special situation
will it be set differently.
Then let's look at this extremely special setting,
for example,
now I put the right-angle line tension,
I just lowered it, right?
Then I just said that
now we put this gold-gauze,
after it is written,
the value direction is the right-angle line,
so when I put the right-angle line,
this stretch performance,
is to make it higher,
that is, after this value is reduced,
you will see the length of this plate,
the left-hand plate,
it slightly increased,
it is slightly increased,
then,
for the right-hand plate,
its horizontal direction is the right-angle line direction,
so you can see that
there is a slight wave here,
a small wave here,
because its stretch performance in the horizontal direction has improved,
you can understand it as this plate,
in the horizontal direction,
it may become a little wider,
so it will have a little wave,
of course,
these values ​​of the left-hand line and the right-hand line,
for our ordinary users,
you probably have a concept to know,
it is used to control
the values ​​of the two horizontal directions,
that is enough,
well,
then under normal circumstances,
in fact,
we will set the values ​​of the left-hand line and the right-hand line
in the same way,
why do you say that,
because your plate,
although its left and right are symmetrical,
but what you put on it,
this fabric,
its,
There is no left and right symmetry in the direction of placement, it is one direction.
So imagine if you are wearing such a dress now,
the number of your two diagonal lines is very different.
Then it can't be symmetrical left and right.
So you will find that there is actually a left diagonal line and a right diagonal line.
It seems that there is nothing like that.
In the past, we only had one diagonal line.
There seems to be no difference from the past.
But it can only be said that with the left diagonal line and the right diagonal line tension,
we can make some more special panels.
For example, when it comes to round panels and fan-shaped panels,
it still has its own role.
Okay, next, we already have this different sand line in our mind.
Its direction will control the effect of different wrinkles.
Yes, if you want to do an asymmetrical cut,
you may be able to adjust the left diagonal line.
The right diagonal line and the left diagonal line,
but for the asymmetrical cutting,
the board shape may be more important than the physical properties you use.
Because the board shape of the board is originally left and right asymmetrical.
Then we will return to our physical properties.
Because I have already demonstrated to everyone just now.
When you set the gold sand and the silver sand,
and you only adjust one of them,
then it will basically only have a challenge in that direction.
So it is the same way.
So here, if we adjust only to the tail, that is, the strength of the tail gusset is increased,
then the stretch performance on the tail of our board will be worse, right?
The vertical direction is the gold direction, the horizontal direction is the tail direction.
Let's take a look now.
When we turn on the simulation,
because our horizontal direction, that is, the tail direction, its stretch performance has become worse.
So all of us, because this fabric is not easy to stretch in the horizontal direction,
the creases will be more obvious.
For example, these creases on your neck,
you can see that these creases are usually vertical or oblique,
such as the position of our bottom white here.
Because of the occurrence of these creases,
it is actually because the board above is wider and the board below is narrower,
then you now make it less stretchable,
it is easier to stretch.
After the creases are created,
these creases in the vertical direction will become more obvious.
Because although it is not easy to stretch in the horizontal direction,
in 3D, it will make the creases in the vertical direction become more obvious.
So if we only change the stretch performance of this tail,
for example, increase the strength of the tail gusset,
you will find that these creases in the vertical direction will become more obvious.
If we turn it over and change the strength of the tail gusset,
and then increase the strength of the gold gusset,
let's take a look again.
If I only change the strength of the gold gusset,
it will not be easy to stretch in the vertical direction,
so its vertical direction will become very tight,
and then it is easy to have creases.
So the shape of the entire creases will change.
It and we only change the strength of the tail gusset,
its difference is very big.
Because if you only increase the strength of the gold gusset,
it will wrinkle in the vertical direction,
and then this wrinkle will significantly affect the length of your clothes.
So when we usually adjust it,
you have to pay a little attention
to determine which direction you want the creases to be more obvious.
Then there is another one,
which is in the direction of the right corner line.
You can understand the right corner line very well.
Then the right corner line is oblique,
the stretchability of the fabric is oblique.
For example, I have raised the right corner line very high here.
I just mentioned that the left corner line and the right corner line
are basically set with the same value.
After opening the simulation,
you will find that it seems that the level of the creases in the vertical direction
and the level of the creases in the vertical direction
are not very different.
But you will always feel that
there are some changes in the overall texture of the creases,
because it will make some oblique creases more obvious,
and then it will be easier to produce these creases.
You can see that after we adjust the right corner line,
the oblique creases like this,
as well as the place of the sleeves,
these oblique creases will become more obvious.
So when you are adjusting the Miao attribute,
if you just want to change some specific features,
for example, the creases in the vertical direction,
you can study a little bit
how the Miao attribute of your fabric is placed.
Well, you are really smart.
Okay.
In fact, when we are adjusting the Miao attribute,
you have to pay a little attention to one thing.
Now you can follow me.
You can pause,
study,
and now,
please put your hands on your clothes.
This is related to real life.
In real life,
our fabric is supported by the creases in the vertical direction
and the oblique creases in the vertical direction.
But your oblique creases do not have creases, right?
Your oblique creases are just like a square right angle line.
You can't see it,
you can't touch it.
But now pull your clothes,
pull your clothes in the horizontal direction,
and pull your clothes in the vertical direction.
Now you feel their stretch performance.
Then pull your clothes in the oblique direction.
Do you feel that it is particularly easy to pull your clothes in the oblique direction?
That is,
the stretch performance on its oblique direction
is easier to stretch than on the horizontal and vertical directions.
Of course,
if you are wearing a sweater now,
you may not feel it very clearly.
But if you are wearing some shirts,
jeans,
you will feel it very clearly.
That's because we,
just like I said before,
your vertical direction and horizontal direction,
they all have creases.
But there are no creases in the oblique direction.
It's just a kind of branching.
Then imagine the long,
uh,
the long and the square.
The width of your level and the length of your value,
they are all smaller than the angle line.
So when you usually set the value,
if you don't know how to set it,
then you can remember a rule.
That is,
the two values ​​of the angle line tension
will always be lower than the value of the gold sand and the tail sand.
You just adjust it according to this idea.
There will be no big mistakes in the end.
Um,
remember this point?
Because it is linked to the real life.
Of course,
if you want to make some special,
special,
this fabric structure,
you can also not comply with this condition.
But,
uh,
for most fabrics,
the two values ​​of the angle line,
you set them to be lower than the gold sand and the tail sand.
Okay,
so,
this is the end of this video.
Thank you for watching.
See you next time.
Yes,
it's because your level and value are all sand lines.
What you write is this,
uh,
that is,
what you write is that it has no sand line.
So,
uh,
it's hard to pull the horizontal and vertical.
And then,
a little more hidden,
in general,
the strength of the gold sand will be higher than the strength of the tail sand.
Uh,
why do you say that?
Because,
you,
when you wear,
when you wear clothes,
this person is wide,
this person is tall and fat,
right?
Then,
your figure is different.
When you wear a piece of clothing,
how many clothes will have a certain elasticity in the horizontal direction,
so that you can have the volume to wear this clothes.
In the vertical direction,
the length of the clothes,
it is basically where to wear,
where to wear.
So,
usually,
the strength of the tail sand,
because the tail sand is the horizontal direction,
the strength of the tail sand will be a little lower than the strength of the gold sand,
but it's not all the case.
But,
uh,
if you don't know how to adjust it,
you can adjust the fabric with this standard first.
Uh,
or it doesn't work.
Your gold sand,
tail sand,
use the same number.
Then,
it's okay to change it later.
Uh,
so,
when we change this,
adjust this fabric,
we,
we can set the number of this diagonal line first,
set the value a little smaller.
Okay,
so,
we just talked about this,
the direction of the sand,
some of the effects of physical properties.
Then,
let's look at some cases.
These cases,
I will introduce these cases to you,
that is,
physical properties.
What are the uses of these different physical properties?
Ah,
because in the usual use process,
you will definitely feel,
oh,
I really don't know how to adjust it.
Okay,
first of all,
let's go back to this gold sand,
tail sand intensity,
because I just told you about gold sand,
tail sand,
and the diagonal line.
These four properties,
in fact,
are used to adjust the stretch performance of the fabric.
The stronger the stretch performance,
the more difficult it is to produce wrinkles.
Because this fabric,
it is elastic,
you have to know that the production of wrinkles,
it is all due to the strength,
right?
You have to have some strengths and weaknesses,
and the strength,
leading to this fabric,
it,
for example,
like single-point support,
the single-point support here,
and the support between the two points,
it will all lead to wrinkles.
Then if your stretch performance is better,
in fact,
these wrinkles,
uh,
it,
it will become a little smaller when it receives this force,
so it will cause its wrinkles to be difficult to produce,
right?
Ah,
so if you have seen our previous tutorial,
it will have a little impression,
a little impression,
about these physical properties.
Ah,
here,
for example,
I will now reduce the strength of this gold sand a little bit.
Well,
just now,
ah,
I don't know if you have seen me before,
when I was clicking on this fabric,
when we were opening this project just now,
click here on this fabric,
ah,
let me take a look,
this is the one we just talked about.
When I use the edit text tool in the 3D window to click on this position,
you can see that this direction is our gold,
right?
So if I reduce its,
uh,
gold sand intensity,
it will be in this direction,
its stretch performance will be better,
right?
For example,
now I have reduced its gold sand intensity to 5.
In fact,
it will be more significantly affected by our gold sand direction.
So you can see,
because this direction is the gold,
this direction is the tail,
this is the length of this edge,
how long it is controlled by the tail.
Because the gold is here,
the tail is here,
then this side,
the gold is the vertical direction,
so you can see it with your own eyes,
you can see that there seems to be no change here,
but here your version will become longer.
This is what I just mentioned to everyone.
Let's review it again,
let's review it,
that is,
you will find that after its gold sand intensity changes,
the length of the entire fabric will also shrink back,
because it is not easy to stretch,
its fabric itself,
its elasticity will become poor,
it is not easy to stretch,
the fabric is self-reliant,
it will resist this gravity,
so it will become shorter.
If you reduce the strength of the gold sand,
the strength of the tail sand,
and the strength of the diagonal line,
it will be very, very low,
then this fabric will be like a study room,
it will have a very strong elasticity itself.
For example,
now I am going to make some adjustments to the strength of the tail sand,
because the tail sand is the edge that supports between the two points,
it is our tail sand,
if I now reduce the strength of the tail sand,
it is very obvious that you can see this edge,
because its elasticity has become stronger,
so this edge,
it will bend down,
and the shape of its fold will be different from just now,
so when we understand this specific physical attribute,
it must be remembered before it has any effect,
it is still a little related to your sand direction,
yes,
so the second point is,
so in the 2D window,
you go to check each point,
its sand line direction is not as intuitive as in the 3D window,
so sometimes you can use this 3D window,
the editing text tool to check each point,
now, for example,
we increase the strength of the diagonal line a little bit,
then it will not be easy to stretch in the diagonal line direction,
that is,
the fold of these diagonal lines will become more obvious,
because our fabric,
it is not completely,
the gold is gold,
the tail is tail,
the corner is the corner,
it has some gradually crossed some of this,
well,
that is,
its sand line direction is gradually crossed like this,
so it will also have some influence on each other,
just say you want to adjust the specific position,
you can use this sand line direction,
do a reference,
that since it talks about the strength of the gold tail,
and the strength of the diagonal line,
then here I want to give you a knowledge,
that is,
I haven't mentioned it just now,
the strength of the gold tail,
the strength of the diagonal line,
is controlled by whether the fabric is easy to stretch,
well,
if now I have put pressure on these panels,
here we have applied a pressure of 5 to the panel,
you can see that now the panel is in the 3D window,
it looks like a QQ talk,
this,
is a square,
square,
square.
Now we will reduce the strength of the gold tail sand a little,
when I reduce the strength of the gold tail sand,
the strength of the gold tail sand,
this material becomes easy to stretch,
you imagine it into a balloon,
it turns into a balloon,
or something like that after pressure,
you will see that its stretching performance has transformed,
it becomes easy to stretch,
I still use the same pressure.
This,
立方体它就会变成另外一种形态立方体它就会变成另外一种形态
它看上去就会更Q弹一些它看上去就会更Q弹一些
防弹衣较鞋的话等一下会有后续会有我们这个直播录播的防弹衣较鞋的话等一下会有后续会有我们这个直播录播的
对那如果现在我们再把它反过来把经纬杀强度还有对角线张力都提高让它变得不容易拉伸对那如果现在我们再把它反过来把经纬杀强度还有对角线张力都提高让它变得不容易拉伸
有点厉害 pipeline
它还是一样没有办法像之前一样变成那么Q弹的棉花糖的样子它会变成一个非常有褶皱的有一些声音版片拿上躲agnome集在一个区域里不 olduğu之后它不容易拉伸所以面料本身非常容易出褶皱哪怕你把压力调到5 他还是一样没有办法像之前一样变成那么Q弹的棉花糖的样子它会变成一个非常有褶皱的有一些生意jve版片含定的力的数值
因为同样是给一样的因为压力是一个恒定的数值恒定的力的数值
他在吹这个版片的时候它在吹这个版片的时候
If the panel is not easy to stretch, it will also be affected by the same force, it will not be like before, because it is easy to stretch and it is very big.
So when you usually do some clothes or some clothes, you find that I give a lot of pressure.
But it just can't hold it, it's like there's no pressure.
Why?
It's probably because the numbers of your stretching performance are set too high.
It can't apply this pressure to get those that are more pungent.
So it depends on what kind of effect you specifically want.
The above is about the strength of our gold tail gauze and the content of the focus line tension.
Next, it's about our bending strength.
Bending strength, it doesn't mean anything.
It's called bending strength.
It's about whether it's easy to bend the fabric.
The higher the bending strength, the harder it is to bend the fabric.
For example, like some leather and cloth, they are some of the thicker fabrics in your imagination.
And it itself has a certain support.
Then its bending strength may be higher.
Like silk and sewing.
These fabrics.
It's thinner.
It's softer.
And you can feel that it's thinner.
You can't say it's soft.
It's more like summer clothes.
Maybe its bending strength is a little bit lower.
Okay.
But in our software.
For these descriptions of physical properties.
It usually can't be covered in one word.
So we can take a look at the effect after adjustment here.
Like bending strength here.
Because it has something to do with whether the fabric is easy to bend.
So when I increase the bending strength.
We can take a look at these bending positions.
Okay.
After my simulation, you will see that after increasing the bending strength.
The fabric will not bend easily.
Just like this.
Because of the force.
The fold will fall down.
So after we increase the bending strength.
These fold up because they are easy to bend.
Become a thinner fold.
Now it's because it's not easy to bend.
It's held up.
The whole fold will look thicker.
A little harder.
In fact, we will mainly make it.
It is understood as.
It's not easy to bend.
It's not easy to hang on.
It's just getting harder.
Right.
Including these lines of us.
You look from the side.
These folds of us.
It will also become harder.
Some.
Become a little wider.
Okay.
If we set this bending strength.
A little higher.
Because bending strength.
It actually.
Not only controls this fabric.
Is it hard to hold.
It also controls your.
The total number of folds.
Because once I put this bending strength.
Cut to a very high, very high, very high time.
Because of the fabric.
It's not easy to bend.
So these.
Because of the fold.
The fold you see.
It will gradually merge.
The number of folds will also change.
Like before.
We will have a lot of small folds.
But because I increased the bending strength.
These small folds.
Maybe they all merge into one.
A big fold.
This is our bending strength.
Number.
Okay.
Then let's take a look at the actual application.
When on the clothes.
For example.
Let's change this bending strength.
Okay.
Here I put the bending strength.
The number is a little higher.
Still the same.
Use our previous principles.
Is.
The bending strength of the front and back.
Is the front and back.
The number is relatively large.
Then the diagonal number.
Is a little smaller.
Okay.
Let's take a look at the simulation effect.
Then because of our bending strength.
Increase the fabric.
It's not easy to bend.
So these folds.
It looks like.
From the just a little bit.
The fold.
Becomes thicker.
Then the whole outfit.
It looks like.
It will be harder.
The same.
This material.
If I put it now.
This bending strength.
Reduce again.
Okay.
After reducing the bending strength.
Let's take a look again.
First of all.
Look at my fold on the finger.
My fold.
These fine.
Some folds.
It's changed a lot.
They're all out.
And then.
The whole outfit.
It looks like.
It's like it's on your body.
And then.
It's also the same.
Will become.
Higher.
Okay.
This is the bending strength.
Then.
It's up to us.
The deformation rate.
And the deformation strength.
Deformation rate.
Deformation strength.
It's what you usually.
It's rare to notice.
Two.
Well.
It's two.
Two material attributes.
Type.
But it's actually.
It will be for you.
In the process of making clothes.
It will have a very obvious impact.
Then.
Our default fabric.
Its deformation rate.
It's all zero.
What does deformation rate mean?
Deformation rate.
It's a fabric.
It's not easy.
Because of some.
Other external forces.
Or some.
Well.
By.
Some.
Other forces.
Caused.
Its.
Deformation.
Difficulty.
So.
After the deformation.
Here.
I will give you a secret.
Which goes
This size.
I think.
I like.
Can.
Manufacture.
A lot of.
Deformation.
And expression.
Like this.
Imagine.
Ordinary fabric.
it will have some support force, some other force,
but not in the case of the influence of its own gravity.
Its fold position, like these curves, it will have a sudden change.
It won't be like these vertical positions,
which is a natural curve direction.
So these deformation rates and deformation intensity,
you can see it as a fold that is separately controlled and generated.
Let's take a look at it.
In a random situation, the deformation rate is 0,
which means that its bending intensity will not change in the fold position.
The deformation intensity below is specialized in,
the deformation rate is equivalent to determining a range.
The fold in this range, its physical properties,
in fact, it is not its physical properties, only its bending intensity,
will be multiplied by this percentage of the deformation intensity below.
For example, your deformation rate is 80%,
then this fold will have 80% of the position to generate deformation.
This bending intensity will be reduced.
After the bending intensity is reduced,
the curve of this fold will become a little sharper.
Because its bending intensity changes,
that is, its bending intensity value,
that is, the bending intensity value of the fold position,
will be reduced.
It will no longer bend like this,
the bending intensity is high,
and then its fold is flat.
So when we usually use a default fabric,
you will find that I change the value below,
why does it seem to be no difference?
That's because we didn't apply the deformation rate from 0 to it first.
Because when the deformation rate is 0,
the fold position will not apply the deformation intensity below.
Because it has not been deformed yet.
The bending intensity of the fold position
will be the same as the bending intensity of other positions.
Then it makes no sense to set the deformation intensity below.
So we apply a deformation rate to it first,
so that the fold position begins to deform.
So we set the deformation rate for it first.
For example, set the deformation rate of 80 here.
Setting the deformation rate of 80
is equivalent to the fold position of 80%
will be deformed.
Then the deformation intensity below is,
for example, the deformation intensity is 0,
then the final bending intensity of the fold position
is this 0 times the value above.
How much is this? 60.
That's 0.
So you can imagine the deformation rate as
it is only for places where fold has already occurred.
In fact, it is not,
but it will have a more complex mathematical logic.
But you can imagine it as
only for places where fold has occurred.
There is no need to understand it too carefully.
So your understanding is OK.
Then there will be a deformation intensity below.
I just talked about it.
The deformation intensity is actually a percentage.
You see its value unit is from 0 to 1.
So it is from 0% to 100%.
It is to multiply the bending intensity above
to multiply the value below
to calculate the final position.
That is, the bending intensity of our fold position.
OK.
In this case,
we apply a deformation rate to it.
Then we don't change the deformation intensity first.
OK.
When the deformation intensity is not changed,
you will see that after we start the simulation,
the fold will become more and more fine.
More and more fine.
And the number of fold we have in the whole
is basically the same.
Right?
It only affects what?
It affects the fold we have already created.
This fold is fine by itself.
It doesn't matter if you can't understand it now.
You will understand it later.
You will understand it later
when you see our strength.
OK.
Then the following is our deformation intensity.
Just like I just said,
because the bending intensity of the fold position
cannot be calculated according to the ordinary
bending intensity of this connection.
So the deformation intensity,
for example, when it is 0,
this position is the greatest degree of
the bending intensity of the fold.
So if we set the deformation intensity
higher here,
for example, 20,
then it is 0.2 times 80 above,
that is, the bending intensity of the fold position
is probably 16 and 12.
You can see that the bending position
has become a little wider by itself.
OK.
Understand?
Let's take a look at the comparison again.
Through the comparison,
you can see that
it was originally a fine fold.
It will become thicker in the fold position again.
It is because at the beginning
of the default deformation,
the bending intensity was too low.
OK.
Then you can see that
we have this excessive position,
because this is the fold position.
This is a fold,
and then this is where we
go from the ordinary flat version
to this fold position.
It actually has no
great impact.
Because what we just changed is the deformation intensity.
It is only for the fold position.
It does not affect this position.
It only affects these excessive edges.
OK.
Physical properties.
It is a little difficult for everyone to learn.
I also understand.
So we will have some specific solutions
to show you later.
OK.
For example,
I now reduce its deformation rate
from 80 to 20.
OK.
When the deformation rate is 80,
it is equivalent to 80% of the fold position
will start to apply this deformation intensity.
The deformation rate is 20,
then it is equivalent to 20% of the fold position.
The deformation intensity will be applied.
The deformation rate will be reduced.
That is to say,
this fold position
may have been
soft in most places.
Now it will become
soft in a few places.
The other positions are still hard.
So this fold position
will look a little harder.
It is as fine as before.
That is,
when its deformation rate is relatively high,
we now reduce the deformation rate.
The whole thing will still apply some
of our original bend intensity.
This bend intensity
has not been reduced.
OK.
Everyone must be a little dizzy now.
You must be thinking,
can you be more intuitive
and tell me what is the deformation rate
and what is the deformation intensity?
It doesn't matter.
Let's imagine this version
as a small mountain.
OK.
This is a small mountain.
Right?
This is a fold.
This is also the flat one.
That is,
the position of the ordinary fabric.
OK.
Then from this small mountain down
is our deformation rate.
OK.
This is the mountain peak.
This is the corner of the mountain.
The deformation rate
is down from here.
The percentage of this section.
For example,
my deformation rate is 80%.
Then it may be from the top of the mountain
to this mountain peak.
This whole section
will be deformed.
It will become more and more sharp.
More and more sharp.
If you only have 20%,
only the top of the mountain
will change its deformation intensity.
Because you see,
this,
uh,
everyone imagines the slope of this curve.
Will it be too abstract to say this?
It's this deformation rate.
That is,
from here,
is it all this curve?
It's still more smooth.
It will become more steeper
when it reaches the top of the mountain.
This is because
our deformation intensity
has decreased sharply.
Because the bending intensity,
it is
higher.
The higher it is,
the more difficult it is to bend.
This curve will be smoother.
OK.
I will
temporarily admit that
everyone understands.
OK.
Then my deformation rate is 80%.
When this mountain peak
has 80% of the position,
there will be deformation.
If I change the deformation rate to 50%,
then this mountain peak
may be from the top of the mountain.
There will be deformation from the top of the mountain to the top of the mountain.
Below the top of the mountain,
it will all apply
the same curve as these connection positions.
Yes,
the deformation rate is equivalent to the adjustment range.
Adjustment range
is where to start deformation.
If,
but it is from the top to the bottom,
it is not from the bottom to the top.
Because you want to get closer to the top of the mountain,
is this mountain more sharp?
The head of the mountain is more sharp.
You imagine it as this.
You imagine it as a mountain.
The higher the mountain is at the top,
the more sharp it is.
So when the deformation rate is 80%,
it is this mountain.
It may have 80% of the position
is steep.
Yes, it starts from the top of the mountain to the bottom,
not from the top of the mountain to the top.
Yes.
Too smart.
OK.
So you can take a look.
If I now change its deformation rate from 80% to 50%,
it will become more steep from the top of the mountain.
When you look at this curve from the naked eye,
you will feel that it seems to be a little wider,
and the shadow position becomes a little more blurred.
This is because we have reduced the deformation rate.
If I now reduce the deformation rate a little more,
the deformation rate is changed to 10%.
OK, let's take a look again.
When it is changed,
it is equivalent to from the top of the mountain to here.
It may only have 10% of the position.
There will be a little change here.
The bottom position becomes harder.
Because the bending strength is no longer in the sharpness.
So if you look at it from the top view,
you will feel that the fold position of this plate
becomes thicker and harder.
This is the deformation rate.
But in fact,
it affects your fabric more.
This value is the deformation rate.
This value is the deformation strength.
So the deformation rate is here.
I'm just telling you.
If you are a friend who wants to learn about physical properties,
I just tell you that the deformation rate is this.
But in general,
if you are a marvelous designer,
relatively ordinary,
or I just want to use this property,
you can set the deformation rate to 80 or 60.
OK.
But you still have to learn.
If our deformation rate is 0,
like I just said,
when the deformation rate is 0,
it is the same from the top of the mountain to the bottom.
It is not changed.
So its rate of attraction is flat.
It's not like this.
It's the cut rate.
Cut rate.
It doesn't change much.
Its entire bending strength,
its transition is the same.
This is the deformation rate.
At this time,
if you change the deformation strength below,
it's useless.
Because the whole mountain is not cut.
It's all flat.
No matter how you change the deformation strength,
it has no application range.
If you simulate it again,
you will find that there is no difference at all.
So when we set the deformation rate,
you just have to set some special values.
For example, 0.
When it is 0,
it is not deformed at all.
You don't have to change the deformation strength below.
When will you use these values?
You want my fold.
I set the bending strength.
I want it to be in the final form.
In the current state,
the final fold,
you set the deformation rate to 0.
When the fold is the widest,
Then,
there is a deformation rate of 60 or 80.
It depends on your mood.
60 or 80 is fine.
Because they are not very different.
You just use 60.
The deformation rate of these four values,
you set them all to 60.
Then you use the deformation strength
to adjust its width.
Another one is the deformation rate of 100.
We will talk about the deformation rate of 100 later.
Because the deformation rate of 100
is a very special situation.
For example,
we set the deformation rate here
and set the deformation rate to 50.
Let's change the deformation strength.
I just talked about it.
If my deformation rate is set,
it is still deforming.
But the deformation strength is a percentage.
If the deformation strength is 100%,
even if the fan starts to deform,
the bending strength does not decrease.
Because it is still 1.
It is not 1.
If it is 0.5 times 0.8,
it will become smaller.
It is still the original value.
After you look at the simulation,
you will find that this version has not changed.
It is the same.
It is because your deformation strength is 100.
Because it does not deform.
It is the same as your deformation rate is 0.
This is also a special value.
At this time,
you will find that no matter how I change the deformation rate,
it is the same.
Because it is also equivalent to,
the bending position does not decrease.
The bending strength does not decrease.
There is no difference.
Next, let's look at a special case.
I just talked about it.
When the deformation rate is 100.
What does it mean when the deformation rate is 100?
Yes.
When the deformation rate is 100,
it is our version.
But, it
Bobby.
You are really good.
But you will also see that the shorter version on the top will also have some creases because it is forced due to the gap between the lines, which leads to some creases on it.
Then the long version at the bottom has some creases.
If I now set the deformation rate to 100, because when the deformation rate is 100, it is equivalent to this mountain.
The whole mountain is connected to the plain.
It's starting to happen.
What kind of thing will happen then?
Let's take a look.
When your deformation rate is all 100, open the simulation.
Pay attention to the position of this vertical line.
It's gone.
It's gone when it's folded.
because
The mountain is connected to the mountain.
Its creases have piled up a lot of small creases in this position.
It's not as big as the bottom.
Because it has too many small creases piled up here.
In addition, when the deformation rate is 100, all the creases are starting to apply the sharpness of the bending strength.
Its most obvious position is along the line of the gap.
So we just have to do this.
You can also say that the deformation rate has three special values.
or 80
It depends on the mood.
Then you just take it as 60.
and 100
When it's 100, the creases in the line of the gap will be flattened.
But because of the deformation rate.
When you set it to 100, the fabric itself is particularly easy to deform.
Whether it's because of the deformation of the line of the gap.
Or because of some of your dynamics.
Do some dynamic movement.
When you do these things.
It has some external forces.
It will deform.
So it will bring a problem.
It may not be stable.
So be careful when using the deformation rate as 100.
Generally speaking, we only set the deformation rate to 100 when we make these dresses.
Just like this.
When we usually make dresses.
You say, I don't know how to change the panel.
In fact, the way you change the panel.
It can get the same effect.
It's just that sometimes you will say.
Oh, it's too much trouble to change the panel.
I don't know how to change this panel.
Now I just want to erase the creases in the line of the gap.
But I still have to keep the creases at the bottom.
Then you set the deformation rate to 100.
OK.
This is some content about our deformation rate and deformation intensity.
The first is the deformation rate.
Here is the location of the deformation rate.
Yes.
You can see that the deformation rate does not affect this.
Because of the force generated by the fabric itself.
This is because the force generated by the fabric itself.
It doesn't have the function of the sewing line.
It's the bottom line.
So it doesn't affect the bottom line.
This big fold.
It only affects the small fold above.
OK.
Next, let's take a look at the actual application.
Now let's change the deformation intensity.
I just talked about the deformation rate.
You don't care.
The top is 60.
You set it to 60.
Don't care about it.
Next, let's look at the deformation intensity.
Reduce the deformation intensity.
It only controls the fold that is generated.
What is the fold that only controls the fold that is generated?
You can take a look.
Because we mentioned it just now.
You change.
If you change it directly.
If only only change the deformation intensity.
The deformation intensity is low.
There will be many small extra fold.
A lot of fold.
If the deformation intensity is high.
Will cause the fold to be less.
Because each fold will be big from the small fold.
Right?
So if we only change the deformation intensity.
Because it only affects the position of the fold.
So it doesn't affect the overall fold.
Let's take a look at the contrast.
You will find that only the fold position is deeper.
It's more obvious.
Then the fold becomes thinner.
This is suitable for what situation, that is, you now feel that I have a dress, its fold distribution, I think it's ok, the overall shape, I think it's ok, but I just want it to be a little thinner, you just change the deformation intensity, reduce it a little, understand?
Ah, for example, if I turn it over now, I just want it to be folded, it is the position where the fold is, and I want it to be wider, then I will set the deformation intensity to be higher, for example, the deformation intensity is 50, like this.
Ah, but here I am going to show you a more special time.
I haven't talked about it just now, the deformation intensity, it is a percentage, it will be multiplied by 10,000 to the intensity.
For example, if I reverse it now,
just now we are the deformation intensity is 10, the bending intensity is 50, right?
Now I will turn it over and show you.
If we turn it over, what will happen?
Ok, turn it over, let's simulate it.
Although its fold is still the same value,
but because when you change the bending intensity, the bending intensity, it is useful overall, it is not only useful in the fold position,
it will cause that when you start to simulate,
do we have a lot of this kind of fine, small, extra fold,
the whole fabric will look thin, and then there is no thickness, and then there is extra fold.
This is, even though we are,
the deformation intensity in the imagination and the bending intensity are related values, but you still have to pay attention, their usage is different.
The bending intensity is used on the whole dress,
like the left side is the bending intensity, I set it relatively low,
and then when the deformation rate is set relatively high,
the right side is to turn it over, my bending intensity is relatively high, when the deformation rate is relatively low,
you can feel it very clearly.
The fold, you see, the position of the fold may be almost rough,
but overall, the fold on the right side will be cleaner,
and then it will keep most of the obvious folds I want.
And then it's just for these fold positions that are generated,
for example, I want to make it thinner, these.
Yes, so the bending intensity is adjusted to the large, and the deformation intensity is slightly adjusted.
And then, if you only use these two numbers,
you set the deformation rate to 60 forever, and you don't want to change it.
Unless you use 0 or 100 when it's particularly special,
you use 60 at other times.
That's it.
Okay.
Then I believe that after you have seen these two comparisons objectively,
you may have some understanding of physical properties,
that is, this is how physical properties work.
Yes, the deformation rate is adjusted to the range,
but in most cases, you can use 60 for the deformation rate.
Of course, what is the deformation rate you want to study?
I just told you about it, didn't I?
The above is about some of our physical properties,
and then there are some numbers below.
Okay.
Below there are, for example, our internal damping,
internal resistance, density, and friction coefficient.
These, in fact, are only related to the simulation.
This is internal damping.
Internal damping has nothing to do with our static simulation.
Internal damping is related to when we do animation.
The lower the internal damping value, the smoother it is.
For example, the air resistance is lower.
For example, the internal damping is 1 under normal circumstances.
Sometimes you want the fabric to rebound a little slower,
the feeling of its movement is more obvious.
It's not that the feeling of the movement is more obvious.
Maybe when you simulate it, you want it to move more like resistance.
For example, if you move the fabric in the water,
you may need to increase the internal damping a little bit.
Sometimes, in order to simulate stability in animation,
it will also increase the internal damping a little bit,
to prevent too intense shaking and shaking.
Then density, as the name suggests, is the density of the fabric itself.
It also has something to do with strength.
It has more to do with animation.
Because if the density of your skirt is relatively low,
if you add some slightly large-scale movements,
because the density of the skirt is relatively low,
the skirt will fly up.
Because you shake it too much,
you can reduce the density appropriately.
It will be more stable.
But because of density,
it actually still affects the weight.
So when you look at it, it may be more...
It's not so...
It still has weight.
When you look at it, it doesn't look like a light skirt.
So you may have to cooperate with some pressure at that time.
It's these fixed forces that give it some special effects.
Do you understand?
Pressure is a very strong force.
It will blow up your skirt.
Pressure...
When you choose a pattern,
I have told you this little trick many times.
You click on the pressure.
The left arrow can be entered after the small number.
Then you can use this value to make a balance with the pressure.
Let the fabric become more...
Like this.
The last is friction coefficient.
Friction coefficient is the friction force.
The larger the value,
the more friction between the fabric and the human body.
The greater the friction force,
the more difficult it is to slide.
It's also related to animation a little bit.
Of course, when doing static,
for example, when doing some belts,
and some comfortable things,
we will increase the friction coefficient.
And when you tie,
in order to prevent the fabric from sliding,
we will increase the friction coefficient a little bit.
But for the shape of the fold,
the last three elements are actually less affected.
Okay.
Do you have any other questions?
If you send a message to the backstage,
you will receive our updated motherboard.
Well,
I will send it to the backstage.
But come back,
I will send it to the backstage and the other people will receive the message.
We will send the message to each of you.
But everyone has to do the same.
We will send Toad to the backstage instead of my avatar.
So,
follow us on the Bilibili facebook page.
Please follow our broadcast.
Also,
follow our group WQ way.
So,
everyone can pay more attention to our live broadcast space.
Pay more attention to our official account .
I will post more teaching videos, and some information related to it
I'm not tired, I'm not tired, I think everyone is very tired because today is Friday night
Thank you for coming to watch our live broadcast
This is also our first live broadcast this year
And thank you for your support
If you have any educational videos or live content that you want to learn, you can tell me
Then we will also have a technical support group, and if you have any questions, you can also ask in the technical support group
I will answer your questions at the end of the week
There are friends in our group during the weekend, you can also learn by yourself
Right
ah
You are too kind. I am very grateful to everyone for your support, because this is the first live broadcast this year, and we haven't seen each other for a long time.
Thank you very much for your support. I hope that in the future we will have so many friends watching every live broadcast.
If you like our videos and our live broadcasts, please remember to click and follow.
If you think our channel is good, you can share it with your family and friends.
If you have any questions during the process of using AMD, you can also send a private message to our backstage, or leave a message in the comments below our video, or ask questions in our QQ group.
Do you have any questions today?
I see that there are friends asking if there is a chance to work at AMD.
You can send me a private message in the backstage.
Let's see if there is a possibility of cooperation.
Thank you very much for your support all the time.
Our software will also make major updates this year.
I hope everyone can support us in the future.
These updated content.
and
Some of our future teaching videos.
If you like it, please remember to like, collect, forward, and comment.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Thank you for watching our live broadcast.
Thank you all.
The Frenzy Turn mode is not compatible.
This is written in our official document.
I have already written it in our special column.
The first one is when you export.
If you choose to merge.
When you choose Turn on the Frenzy line.
Its top point will merge.
Secondly, if you are with thickness.
Because of Turn, it will identify.
For example, like this.
What about Turn?
It actually identifies you.
Two-layer panels will be identified as two layers.
Because if you open a single display.
This is a single display.
Alt2 is a single display.
When it is only without thickness.
It looks like two layers.
But if you press Alt1.
After opening the thickness.
You will find.
In fact, this layer.
It is calculated the thickness.
So when you look at it.
Sometimes you will say.
There is a gap in the middle.
It's not because of the gap.
It's because we will.
Calculate it.
Calculate with the thickness together.
So when you open a single display.
When you open a single display.
When there is no thickness.
You will feel that there is a gap.
Then when you export OBJ.
Or export other formats.
Choose the merge top point.
It will follow the Frenzy line.
To merge this top point.
On the top of the panel with its Frenzy.
So when you export.
If you don't choose the merge top point.
You look like two layers.
If you choose the merge top point.
It will merge.
Let me tell you something else.
The basic logic of the merge top point.
It follows the Frenzy line.
So if you are in the creation.
After this is repeated.
That's because the repeated version.
It doesn't have its own Frenzy line.
Then we need to export it.
When you choose.
Click on the merge top point.
There will be a few options when exporting.
That is, if the merge is close to the top point.
It is not calculated according to the Frenzy line.
It is according to the distance between the top point and the top point.
It is calculated according to the distance between the top point and the top point.
If you choose to merge.
Then it is according to the Frenzy line.
As a basic logic to merge.
For example.
There is a Frenzy line between these two lines.
Then I will merge this side.
On the side where it has a Frenzy line.
So usually.
Because everyone asks.
There are many friends with TURN questions.
So everyone is free.
You can also pay attention to our column.
There are also some common questions in the column.
Answered.
If everyone has no questions.
Then our live broadcast today.
Maybe it's over here.
Also very grateful to everyone.
So hard.
It's so late to watch our live broadcast.
If you are friends who watch the live broadcast.
Also thank you.
It's been hard to watch the live broadcast for so long.
See now.
Thank you very much for your support.
We will work hard to make our software better and better.
Some videos and lessons in the local language.
It is also on the way to production.
I wish you all the best.
Have a happy new year.
Work happily.
Bye bye.